The sys library is versatile in allowing us
to import other modules, manage files, and
run command-line arguments. The sys library also
allows one to work with system-based commands,
such as changing file paths and doing what we will
demonstrate in this 614-sys file, exiting an app,
like a game being played. On line 1 of this code,
I have the import sys command to import the sys
library. Then, lines 3 through 6 simulate gameplay
to where one has three lives in the game. When the
loop is done, the game is done. The sys.exit
command on line 7 terminates the Python script
immediately, offering a way to exit the script
gracefully. Sometimes, when working with apps,
one needs to be able to exit an app gracefully
rather than have an app generate an error,
and sys.exit allows for that graceful exit. I will
run this code, we see two messages, and then the
game exits. Next, let’s see how this sys module
works with command-line arguments. I will switch
over to this 614-command file, and here, we see
the import sys module on line 1. On line three, we
see the sys.argv for the first time. Sys.argv is
used as a placeholder for a command-line argument,
as we will see shortly. Sys.argv[0] is always
the file name, 614-command.py in this case. The
filename that we will read is set to sys.argv[1]
on line 3. On line 4, we have a print statement
acknowledging the specified file name. Then, on
lines 6 thorugh 8, we have a with statement that
opens and reads the file. To run this file, I will
switch to a command prompt where I have already
navigated to the folder containing these files. I
will type python 614-command.py 614-command.txt.
614-command.py is system argument 0, or sys.argv
0, as again, this is the file we are working with.
614-command.txt is system argument 1, or sys.argv
1, the file that is being opened and read. I will
select the Enter key on the keyboard, and we see
both the acknowledgment message and the contents
of the text file used in this command. We have
looked at a few libraries over these last several
topics. This group of exam objectives does not
call for analyzing code, so this review project
will have you finish a code example in progress
instead of doing that. Use the 614-analyze
file as your source, and use the Review 6.4
exercise in your project workbook to answer
the questions related to the file. I will reveal
the answers to those questions in the next video.